<Help>
  <Topic Title="Basic Movement">
    Use the touchpad at the bottom left side of the screen to move.
    Tap it once to jump.
    This can also be configured to use directional buttons instead of the pad.
    \n\n
    Use the touchpad at the bottom right side of the screen to look around.
    Tap it once to jump.
    You can also drag your finger across any area of the screen to look.
    \n\n
    Falling from large heights will injure you.
    \n\n
    You can tweak control scheme of the game in the Controls and Sensitivity settings.
    Experiment with various options, for example you may find you prefer buttons to touchpads, or split touch with crosshair to regular controls.
    Controlling a first person game on a small touchscreen may look difficult, but once you get the hang of it, it is no different than using a gamepad or a mouse.
    Because you can touch any part of the screen at any time, some actions like block digging or placement may even be easier.
    \n\n
    Some cheap devices have low quality touch screens or buggy touch drivers.
    They might intermittently drop active touch points, or mix them up if touched in more than one point at once.
    These are best avoided as playing on them is extremely frustrating.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Sneaking">
    Sneaking is useful if you want to move slowly and carefully, for example to avoid falling near the edge of a tall crevice.
    \n\n
    To toggle sneak mode, press the sneak button on the right side of the screen.
    When sneak mode is enabled, your movement will be restricted at edges to prevent you from falling.
    \n\n
    Sneaking also makes your movements much quieter, allowing you to come closer to certain animals without scaring them away.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Flying">
    Flight is only available in Creative Mode.
    To toggle fly mode, tap the flight button on the right side of the screen.
    \n\n
    Flying is much faster than walking and allows you to quickly get to otherwise inaccessible areas.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Climbing Ladders">
    Ladders can be crafted from wooden sticks.
    Once placed on a vertical wall, they allow you to climb the wall easily.
    \n\n
    It's safest to climb the ladder when facing it.
    This is true both for climbing upwards and downwards.
    \n\n
    Consequently, the best way to climb down a ladder is to approach it backwards, as you would do in real life.
    \n\n
    You can jump off the ladder at any time
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Riding Animals">
    You can ride certain animals, such as horses or camels.
    Riding an animal lets you move more quickly and view the world from a higher vantage point.
    \n\n
    To mount an animal, get close to it and wait for it to stop.
    The sneak button will turn into mount button.
    Press it to mount/dismount.
    \n\n
    To successfully ride an animal, you need a saddle, which can be crafted from leather and wooden sticks.
    When the animal is saddled, its behavior changes and it becomes more friendly to you.
    \n\n
    Do not mount an unsaddled animal, it will not like it.
    \n\n
    You can also ride boats in the same way as animals.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Hunger">
    You need to eat to stay alive.
    If you don't eat for a long time, your character will start complaining about it and eventually losing health, until he dies.
    In addition to that, if you're hungry, you don't regenerate health.
    \n\n
    To eat, drag an edible item to the eat rectangle in the body panel.
    Your character will inform you whether he is still hungry.
    \n\n
    Food can be obtained from many sources in the game.
    The obvious one is hunting edible animals, such as cows, birds and wildboars.
    Keep in mind that hunting may be dangerous, and the supply of animals will quickly dry up in nearby areas, forcing you to search further.
    \n\n
    An alternative to hunting is farming.
    Farming lets you create a sustainable source of food, although it may require lots of preparatory work and further maintenance.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Stamina">
    Your character is not infinitely strong.
    When you perform a tiring action for a long time without break, you will tire and start panting.
    \n\n
    When you are panting, your performance is lower than when you are rested.
    You will move and dig slower, and you will not be able to perform high jumps.
    \n\n
    Some of the actions that are tiring: running, jumping, swimming, digging.
    \n\n
    It is especially dangerous to get tired when you are in water, because you can't rest while swimming.
    Watch for early signs of panting, and get out of water immediately.
    When you get exhausted while in water, you will start drowning and die unless the shore is very near.
    \n\n
    Be careful, it's easy to get tired when running away from dangerous animals.
    This can have fatal consequences for obvious reasons.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Digging Blocks">
    In Survivalcraft, the entire world is destructible.
    \n\n
    To dig a block, press it and hold your finger.
    Digging cracks will appear as the block is being dug.
    \n\n
    Some blocks take a very long time to dig without proper tools. 
    Digging some blocks, such as glass, will destroy them.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Placing Blocks">
    To place a block, select it from your inventory so that you are holding it in your hand.
    Then tap the face of an existing block, where you want the new block to be attached.
    The block will be placed there immediately, unless it is impossible for some reason.
    \n\n
    Certain items behave differently if attached to different parts of an existing block.
    For example, trapdoors can be attached to the top or bottom parts with different results.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Interacting With Blocks">
    Certain blocks are interactive.
    Some examples of interactive blocks: doors, chests, crafting tables, furnaces, buttons.
    \n\n
    To interact with a block, tap on it.
    This will invoke the action associated with the block.
    \n\n
    For example, if you tap on a closed door, it will open.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Editing Blocks">
    Some blocks are editable.
    Examples of editable blocks: crossbow, memory bank, musket, truth table.
    \n\n
    Editable blocks are marked with an edit icon in your inventory.
    \n\n
    To edit a block in the inventory, select it so that you hold it in your hand.
    If the selected block is editable, sneak button will turn into edit button.
    \n\n
    To edit a block which is placed on the ground, stand close to it and point center of the screen at the block.
    If the block in front of you is editable, it will be highlighted and sneak button will turn into edit button.
    \n\n
    Editing lets you change advanced properties of blocks.
    For example editing a crossbow will let you draw it and load a bolt.
    Editing a truth table lets you see and set the binary values.
    To discover which items are editable, watch out for the edit icon on inventory items.
    \n\n
    If you both hold an editable item in your hand and look at an editable block in the terrain, the item in hand will have precedence.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Throwing Items">
    Certain items can be thrown.
    Some examples of throwable items: stone chunks, spears, bricks, snowballs.
    \n\n
    To throw an item, select it in your inventory, so that you are holding it in your hand.
    Press and hold a point on the screen where you want to throw.
    A throwing sights will appear.
    \n\n
    You can move the sights to refine your aim.
    Once you release your finger, the item will be thrown.
    To cancel a throw, move the sights to the edge of the screen.
    \n\n
    Spears are powerful thrown weapons that do a lot of damage when they hit the target.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Dropping Items">
    All items and blocks can be dropped if you no longer need them.
    \n\n
    To drop an item or block, drag it from the inventory slot and drop it on the screen.
    The item will fly a short distance away and fall to the ground.
    \n\n
    Watch out, if you're standing too close you will immediately pick up the dropped item again.
    \n\n
    Dropping items into fire or magma will destroy them.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Crafting">
    Crafting is a process of making more complicated items out of simpler ones, using a crafting table or the crafting area.
    \n\n
    To craft, you need to place ingredients in the crafting slots in a pattern specific to the item being crafted.
    All crafting recipes are available in RECIPAEDIA.
    \n\n
    There are two sizes of crafting areas: 2x2 and 3x3.
    The smaller area is always available and can be accessed by pressing the crafting button.
    To craft more complicated items on a 3x3 area you need to make a crafting table, place it somewhere in the world and click on it.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Smelting">
    Smelting is thermal processing of substances in a furnace.
    Up to 2 substances can be placed in the furnace at the same time.
    \n\n
    Furnace requires fuel to work.
    You can use anything that is combustible as a fuel, but some fuels are better (longer lasting) than others.
    The best fuel is coal.
    \n\n
    You can leave the furnace while it is smelting. The smelting process will continue while you are away.
    All smelting recipes are available in RECIPAEDIA.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Splitting stacks of items">
    Press and hold the slot containing the stack you want to split for about 1 second.
    A red border will appear around it.
    The slot is now in splitting mode.
    Tap any other empty slot, and one item will be taken from the highlighted slot and placed into the tapped slot.
    \n\n
    This technique can also be used to quickly spread items from one stack to multiple slots, e.g. in a crafting table.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Mining">
    You need to mine to obtain resources needed for crafting and smelting.
    Mining can be as simple as digging in a random place with your bare hands.
    You will however soon discover that it is not an effective way to mine, because digging hard rock by hand takes a very long time.
    \n\n
    You need to craft mining tools, such as a shovel and pickaxe first.
    You also need to dig in different places to find specific resources.
    Caves are a good starting point, because they show you a large cross section through the terrain for free.
    \n\n
    Be aware that some resources, such as diamonds or malachite, require tools made of strong materials to be mined.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Farming">
    Farming allows you to grow a variety of plants for decorative or consumption purposes.
    To grow a plant, you need to obtain its seeds, usually from a fully grown plant specimen.
    \n\n
    Some plants will drop seeds immediately when they are harvested, some will require crafting to extract seeds.
    Some seeds will tolerate poor soil, like dirt or grass.
    Others, like rye or pumpkins, require high quality tilled and moist soil, which has been fertilized with saltpeter.
    To make sure the soil is moist, use bucket to create water channels no further than several blocks away.
    Moist soil is darker than a dry one.
    To further enhance soil quality, sprinkle it with saltpeter (which is a source of nitrogen).
    \n\n
    Plants may take a long time to grow, be patient.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Buckets">
    Buckets are used for transporting fluids, such as water or magma.
    To fill empty bucket with a fluid, you need to find a source block of the fluid.
    For example, all ocean blocks are source blocks of water.
    \n\n
    Holding the empty bucket in your hand, tap the source block to collect it.
    The block will be removed from the world and placed inside the bucket.
    \n\n
    To pour the fluid from the bucket, tap on terrain.
    A new source block of fluid will be created, and the fluid will spread out from there.
    You can collect the placed source block again with the empty bucket.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Dyeing and Painting">
    Some blocks and items can be dyed or painted.
    \n\n
    To paint bricks, stone, wood or other blocks, make a paint bucket of appropriate color and use it on the item you want to paint.
    One bucket is good for painting several dozen blocks, after that it runs out.
    \n\n
    Paint stripper can be used to remove paint and restore blocks to their original appearance.
    \n\n
    To dye clothing, place a piece of clothing with a bucket full of paint in a furnace.
    You can dye clothing multiple times, combining colors.
    \n\n
    You can also dye carpets in a similar way.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Electricity">
	Electricity is a powerful mechanism in the game that can be used to control behavior of certain blocks.
	For example, a lightbulb will produce light when connected to a source of electricity, doors will open or close if activated with an electric signal, and many more.
    \n\n
	If you know a bit about real-world electronics, you should feel at home in Survivalcraft.
	All the familiar devices, such as logic gates (AND, OR, NOT etc.) are present and signals are characterized by voltage.
	You can combine gates to build complex circuits, even computers or video games (check Community Content for some great builds by master electricians).
	There are also sensors, such as pressure plates, photodiodes etc. that produce varying signals depending on conditions around them.
    \n\n
	For descriptions of all available electric devices, check RECIPAEDIA.
    \n\n
	Electric signals in the game are conducted through copper wires and have a voltage that is between 0V and 1.5V, in increments of 0.1V.
	This gives 16 distinct voltage values.
    \n\n
	Digital devices, such as buttons, lightbulbs or doors work only with digital signals that have two possible values: low (0, false, off, no) and high (1, true, on, yes).
	In this case, a voltage below 0.8V indicates low, 0.8V and greater indicates high.
	Most commonly digital signals have voltages of 0V for low and 1.5V for high, but any value below 0.8V will be read as low.
    \n\n
	Analog devices, such as pressure plates or motion detectors work with analog signals.
	They will react to each different value of voltage between 0 and 1.5V, not just low and high states.
	For example, sound generator volume and pitch inputs are controlled by analog voltages.
	The volume and pitch will increase smoothly as the voltages get higher.
    \n\n
	It's good to remember that both analog and digital signals are really the same thing when conducted through the wire, a voltage between 0V and 1.5V.
	Only the way a device interprets the signal's voltage determines whether it is digital or analog.
    \n\n
	Voltage can also be interpreted as a number, with 0V representing 0 and 1.5V representing 15.
	Some devices, such as displays, DAC/ADC converters or counters use this interpretation.
    \n\n
	All electric devices have connections (inputs and outputs) on their sides, and sometimes also on their back (the face attached to the wall).
	On complex devices these are indicated by blue and red dots on edges of the elements.
	Blue means input, red means output.
	Number of dots means number of the connection.
	Simple devices, such as buttons, switches or lightbulbs do not have these dots, because they use one input/output only and can be connected from any side.
    \n\n
	Electric devices can be placed on the walls, and sometimes also on the floor/ceiling. 
	Once placed, they can be rotated so that it's easy to connect appropriate inputs and outputs together with the wires.
    \n\n
	There is a special type of block in the game, called wire-though-block, which is a normal block with a hole drilled and an electric wire threaded though it.
	It is very useful when trying to hide wires from sight, run them though the wall, or prevent them from connecting with other wires.
	It is also the only way to access the "back" connection of devices which have it.
	\n\n
	Electricity in Survivalcraft is processed at a frequency of 100Hz.
	It means that voltage goes from one element to another in 0.01s, irrespective of the length of the wire.
	If you need to delay the signal, you may place some neutral elements in its path (for example an OR gate or a pair of NOT gates).
	Each additional element in the way of the signal will delay it by 0.01s.
	For longer delays use Delay Gate, which can produce very long delays if required.
	\n\n
	Electricity is a complex topic and making large working machines requires some learning, but is very satisfying.
	Simple devices however can be constructed by anyone.
	For example, try placing a button next to the hinges of a door.
	You will notice a wire appeared, clicking the button will now operate the door!
	All this scary talk about voltages, signals, digital and analog, but in reality it's that simple.
	\n\n
	Another easy thing to build might be a light switch.
	Place a lightbulb on the ceiling and a switch (not button) on the wall.
	Then connect them with a wire.
	The switch now operates the light, like in a real room!
	\n\n
	Survivalcraft is more about realism than other games of this type, and electricity is no exception.
	What you learn here, might become invaluable when you get to learn this at school, or have to use it for living.
	\n\n
	Explore and have fun!
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Furniture">
    Furniture blocks are sculpted from up to 16x16x16 smaller sub-blocks.
    Sub-blocks within a single furniture block can be made of different materials and painted to different colors.
    Through crafting, furniture blocks can be combined, made interactive or made to work with electricity.
    Furniture designs can be combined into packs, shared between worlds and uploaded to Community Content.
    \n\n
    To design and create furniture use the hammer tool.
    You need to build the design from regular blocks in the world and then use the hammer on the resulting structure to shrink it down.
    Furniture design window will appear where you can tweak the design by moving it, rotating it and changing resolution (between 2x2x2 and 16x16x16).
    Once you are happy with the design, you can commit it.
    \n\n
    In creative mode, the design will be turned into a single furniture block, and the source blocks from which the design was created will remain in the world.
    In survival modes, the design will be turned into several copies of the furniture block (with number depending on resolution) and the source blocks will be consumed.
    Furniture blocks can be placed in the world in 4 orientations, similar to e.g. a furnace or a ladder.
    \n\n
    Not every block can be used for furniture design.
    For example, dirt or grass are ignored by the hammer tool.
    Allowed materials include: planks, granite, basalt, sand, clay, cobblestone, stone bricks, sandstone, marble, bricks, coal, malachite, diamond, copper, iron, glass, carpet, torches, wicker lamps, water, magma.
    Source blocks of the design can be painted or dyed to make the design more colorful.
    Finished furniture can also be painted, this will cover any colors of the source blocks.
    \n\n
    Certain source blocks have special functions.
    For example a torch/lamp block will cause the furniture to have a fire attached to it in the place of the block.
    The design will also emit light.
    \n\n
    You have to be careful when constructing furniture to avoid placing the design on a base made of allowed material (for example sand).
    The hammer tool will not be able to distinguish between the blocks you placed and the base, and will try to incorporate base into the design.
    This will likely cause "design too large" error, because the maximum size of a design in any dimension is 16 blocks.
    \n\n
    Once the furniture block has been created, you can use crafting table to combine it with other blocks in various ways.
    The following combinations are possible:
    \n\n
    * Combine multiple pieces of furniture into one to create interactive furniture.
    Interactive furniture toggles between its constituing designs on click or on electric signal.
    You can create opening doors, switchable lights, raising platforms etc.
    Up to 9 pieces of furniture can be combined (max capacity of crafting table).
    \n\n
    * Combine exactly one furniture design with an electric button to create a custom button.
    The resulting furniture will act as a button.
    \n\n
    * Combine exactly two furniture designs with an electric switch to create a custom switch.
    The resulting furniture will act as a switch, with two furniture pieces acting as two states of the switch.
    \n\n
    * Combine multiple pieces of furniture with an electric wire to create connected interactive furniture.
    The furniture will work in the same way as interactive furniture, but toggling it will also toggle all neighboring pieces of connected interactive furniture.
    You can create multi-block toggleable structures, for example large doors.
    \n\n
    In the furniture panel in creative inventory you can view and organize your furniture designs.
    Create named furniture sets to categorize the designs.
    The newly created designs are placed in "Uncategorized" set, which has a special function.
    Any design in this set, which does not otherwise exist in the world (no items or placed blocks) will be automatically recycled.
    Be careful and move valuable designs to named furniture sets to avoid accidentally losing them.
    Each named furniture set can be turned into a furniture pack and exported from the world.
    You can later import it to other worlds or upload to Dropbox/SDcard and share with others.
    Furniture packs can also be uploaded to community content.
    \n\n
    There are certain limitations to the furniture system:
    \n\n
    * A furniture block can be made from up to 16x16x16 sub-blocks.
    \n\n
    * The amount of geometry used for a single design cannot exceed 300 triangles (too complex designs with many nooks and crannies are not possible).
    The game uses an intelligent tesselation algorithm that optimizes the geometry, so 300 triangles is plenty for even fairly complex designs, unless you really go over the top.
    To reduce number of triangles, you can for example reduce number of small details, reduce number of painted blocks and fill up any internal holes in the design.
    \n\n
    * You can only have up to 1024 unique furniture designs in the world.
    Every time you paint a furniture or combine it with others, you are creating new designs that count towards the total.
    Unused designs (that do not exist in the world either as items or blocks, and are in the "uncategorized" set in the inventory) are automatically recycled.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Sleeping">
    Sleeping will help restore your health and pass the boring night hours when it's too dark or dangerous to work.
    \n\n
    Even if you are not hurt, you still need to sleep from time to time.
    If you neglect it, your character will start to have short blackouts.
    If you keep active despite this warning, the blackouts will get longer and eventually you will lose consciousness.
    Losing consciousness is very dangerous, because predatory animals will quickly smell you and feast on your unguarded flesh.
    \n\n
    Although you don't need a bed, you can only sleep in a cosy and comfortable place.
    The ground cannot be too hard and the area cannot be too exposed to the elements, or wet.
    \n\n
    Your respawn point is set to a place where you last slept.
    To sleep, open the body screen and press a little sleeping button.
    \n\n
    Note: Sleeping is disabled in the demo.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Body Temperature">
    When you are out in the cold without proper clothes, your body temperature will drop.
    Your view will start to freeze over and you will start losing health.
    Find a warmer place or get near fire to warm and dry yourself.
    \n\n
    Too much warmth will do you no good either, standing too close to a large fire will cause you to overheat.
    \n\n
    Sheltered areas are warmer than outside.
    Plugging all the holes and locking doors will make a shelter warmer still.
    Even a small hole open to the elements will admit draughts and make a large difference to temperature.
    Make a fire inside your shelter to make it homely warm and allow you to take your clothes off.
    \n\n
    Being wet dramatically increases your susceptibility to cold, find a warm place to dry yourself faster.
    \n\n
    The best way to deal with cold is to wear multiple layers of thick, dry clothes.
    You need to cover your entire body, leaving feet or head unclothed will defeat most of the warming effect other clothes have.
    Clothes made of animal fur are best for keeping cold out.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Clothing">
    Wearing clothing provides warmth in cold climates and armor protection during combat.
    You can access clothing interface by using Clothing button.
    \n\n
    There are 4 clothing slots on your body: head, torso, legs and feet.
    Each slot can have multiple clothing items, layered one on top of each other.
    The effects of multiple clothing items combine.
    \n\n
    Not everything can be worn on top of anything else, for example you will not be able to wear a t-shirt on top of a fur coat.
    \n\n
    Wearing thick clothes in one slot while leaving another slot bare will not afford much warmth.
    It's imperative to cover entire body to really benefit from clothing.
    It's the thinnest piece of clothing that determines how much heat you lose.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Armor">
    Wearing armor or thick clothing will reduce or even completely eliminate combat injuries.
    Armor will absorb the hits, so that they damage the armor instead of injuring your body.
    Once the armor receives too much damage, it will disintegrate.
    \n\n
    When you are attacked, you will randomly receive a hit into one of your four body areas: head, torso, legs or feet.
    If there is no armor at that slot, you will receive full injury, irrespective of how much armor you wear elsewhere.
    By far the most likely area to receive hits is torso, followed by legs.
    Wearing torso armor will stop 60% of hits, torso and legs together will stop 80%.
    Head and feet armor is of less importance, unless you want to be 100% safe.
    \n\n
    The strongest armor is made of iron and diamonds.
    Early in the game, you can craft wooden torso armor from sticks and strings.
    It's not very sturdy but will stand a few hits potentially saving your life.
    \n\n
    Even plain clothes have certain armor value, especially thick ones made of leather and fur.
    They do not stop all hits, but only partially reduce the damage.
    \n\n
    Wearing heavy armor will make you sink to the bottom and drown, be careful around deep water.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Boats">
    Boats can be used to travel across large bodies of water quickly and safely.
    \n\n
    If you don't have a boat, you risk drowning from exhaustion or being attacked by dangerous underwater creatures.
    \n\n
    To craft a boat you need lots of wood and a crafting table.
    Once the boat is crafted, it can be placed on the shore and mounted in the same way as a horse.
    \n\n
    You can only control a boat when it is in the water.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Suicide">
    Sometimes when you are stuck, the only option is suicide, so that you can respawn at your last sleeping place.
    \n\n
    To kill yourself, open the body screen and repeatedly press the skull and bones button.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Dropbox">
    The game uses Dropbox service to allow you to download and upload data to/from your device.
    \n\n
    Through Dropbox, you can backup and share worlds with others.
    You can also download custom blocks textures.
    \n\n
    To login to Dropbox, click on the login button on the Dropbox screen.
    If you don't have a Dropbox account yet, you will be able to setup one during the login.
    \n\n
    Once you log in, the Dropbox screen will show you the contents of your online Dropbox folders, and allow you to download the files to your device.
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="SD Card" DisabledPlatforms="Ios, Windows81, WindowsPhone81, Desktop">
    The game allows you to import and export worlds to SD Card for sharing and backup purposes.
    \n\n
    If your device does not have an SD Card, generic external storage folder will be used.
    The location of the data on the device is normally /sdcard/Survivalcraft
  </Topic>
  <Topic Title="Community Content">
    The game allows you to browse a list of worlds and block textures published by other Survivalcraft community members, and download them.
    \n\n
    Once you build something interesting, you can also publish it through this service, and it will appear on the list for anyone to download.
    \n\n
    To publish something, first you need to put it on the internet, so that it's accessible to everyone.
    The easiest place to use is Dropbox, although you can use any other provider.
    Once it's done, you can publish the link to it through "Publish Link" dialog in the game.
    \n\n
    Note: the server does not store your content, only the link.
    Just like a search engine.
    You are responsible for keeping the data accessible through the published link.
    Watch out for exceeding bandwidth limits of your provider, having a link near top of the list will make your content receive multiple thousands of downloads in a short time.
  </Topic>
</Help>